A Guide to the William H. Kiblinger Papers, 1855-2000
Library of Virginia
- Photographs (Box 30-53)
  This is the largest series in the collection. They are organized alphabetically by topic. There are a substantial amount of photographs of various mines, CCC camps, trains and railroad depots, as well as the Church of the Incarnation, Cross Keys farm, flowers, bushes, and trees, buildings in Mineral, Virginia, and the town's centennial celebration and its high school, a county right-of-way construction project, and images taken while he was in the service during World War II. There are also a large amount of photographs of the Butler, Kennedy, Kiblinger, Safley, and Sims families. The researcher should consult the finding aid to the collection for a complete list of topics in this series.
  - Abercrombie, Janice (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Advertisements and Billheads (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Aircraft (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Alhiser (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Allah Cooper Mine (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Amateur Radio Field Day - 28-29 June 1997 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Apperson (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - A.R.E. and A.R.E. Members (Virginia Beach) (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Armenius Mines (Box 30, Folder 9-11)
  - Artifacts/Antiques (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Auction at Mineral Ice Company (D.E. Bumpass) (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Bailey (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Belscher (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Berea Baptist Church (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Berryman (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Bethpage Christian Church (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Birds/Animals (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Birds/Animals (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Walter L. Bishop Residence (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Blake (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Blose (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Bowles Store/Residence (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Boyd Smith Mine (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - "Bracketts" (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Thomas Bronough Residence (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Bumpass Family (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - D.E. Bumpass - Photographs and Postcards (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - David E. Bumpass Residence (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - D.E. Bumpass Store (Mineral, VA) (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - David E. Bumpass, Jr. Auction, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Butler (Box 31, Folder 14-18)
  - Butler Hay Crop (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Butler, Henry K. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - John H. Butler Residence (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Butler, Lewis A. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Butler, Lewis H. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Lewis H. Butler Cemetery (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Butler, Maggie May Lavinia (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - William H. Butler Residence (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Butler, William Samuel (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - William S. Butler Cemetery (Mineral, VA) (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - William S. Butler Residence (Berryman) (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Butler/Towsey Cemeteries (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Byrd Mill (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - CCC Camps (Box 32, Folder 14-15)
  - C & O Railroad Depots (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - C & O Railroad Depots in Louisa County (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Camblin (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Carosi, Adelaide (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Cars/Trucks (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Catherine Furnace (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Cemetery Near Martha Jefferson Hospital (Charlottesville) (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Christian Church Cemetery (Louisa) (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Church of the Incarnation (Box 33, Folder 7-11)
  - Church of the Incarnation - 100th Anniversary (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Church of the Incarnation - Rectory (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Church of the Incarnation - Stained Glass/Altar (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Cofer (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Coins/Currency (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Cold Spring (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Coleman Hotel (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Comic Strips (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Conrad's Store (Elkton, VA) (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - "Contrary" Plantation (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Cook (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Cooper Mill on Contrary Creek (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Crank Building (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Cross Keys Farm (Box 34, Folder 13-15)
  - Cuckoo (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Cuzco (Walton Tavern) (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Daniel/Belvin (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Davis (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Davis Cottage/Tavern (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Davis Turnout (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Dellinger (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Dickinson Store (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Dobbins/Hunt (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Stephen Dunnington House Site (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - The Echo - 1927 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Ellis (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Episcopal Churches (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Ergenbright (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Estes (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Abraham Estes Cemetery (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Farmers Supply Company (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Filming a Movie at Louisa C & O Depot (1993) (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Fire Station - Mineral (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Fireman's Fair and Parade (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Flowers, Bushes, Trees (Box 35, Folder 8-12)
  - Fort Story (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Fredericks Hall (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Frederickville Iron Furnace (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Friedens Church (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Garland Store (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Gibson (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Gold Mines - Pendleton Area (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Gold Scale, ca. 1895 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Gordon (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Grasberger (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Charles Groom Residence (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Daniel Grubbs Residence (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Herman Hall Funeral, Oct. 2000 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Hambleton/Foster (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Hancock Collection (Trevilian Depot) (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Harlowe (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Harper (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Harris (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Samuel Harris Residence (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Harris Cemetery (Pendleton, VA) (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Harris Chapel (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Hendrick (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Hester (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Hester, Agnes Thomas - 91st Birthday (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Hillcrest Cemetery (Louisa, VA) (Box 36, Folder 16-17)
  - Historic Estates (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Hix (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Holladay Mill (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Hollands (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Insects (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Johnson (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Joe Johnson Residence (Fire) (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Jones, Scott Nelson (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Jordan, Ira F. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Julia Mines (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Keane (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - L.A. Kellar Residence (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Keller (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
  - Henry R. Kennedy Cemetery (Mineral, VA) (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - John H. Kennedy Residence (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Kennedy, Virginia Spicer (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Kennon (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Kiblinger Car (Auburn, Indiana) (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Kiblinger - Group Photos (Box 37, Folder 15-16)
  - Kiblinger Homes (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Kiblinger - Miscellaneous (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Kiblinger - Texas Branch (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Kiblinger, Charles W. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Kiblinger, Charles William Porter (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Kiblinger, George Edgar (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
  - George E. Kiblinger Residences (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Kiblinger, Henry Hiram (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Henry Hiram Kiblinger Residence - Contrary Creek (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Kiblinger, Inez (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Kiblinger, Jacob Erasmus Tyree (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Kiblinger, Peter Franklin (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Kiblinger Property Line (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Kiblinger, Robert Peter (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Kiblinger, Sarah E. (Box 38, Folder 14-16)
  - Kiblinger, Sarah E. - Kings Adult Home (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Kiblinger, Sarah E. - Marks Adult Home (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Kiblinger, Sarah E. - Funeral, 23 October 1997 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Kiblinger Shop Building (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Kiblinger Stove (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Kiblinger, Tyree E. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Kiblinger, Vandelia Virginia (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Kiblinger, William Carpenter (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Kiblinger, William Henry (Box 39, Folder 9-11)
  - William H. Kiblinger Residence (Box 39, Folder 12-13)
  - Lacy (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Lake Anna State Park (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Leigh, George (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Lett Mine (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Liggon (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Little League/Cecil K. Luck Field (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Lloyd (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Longway (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Louisa - Buildings (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Louisa County Airport (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Louisa County - Bird's Eye Views (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Louisa County - Churches (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Louisa County Courthouse (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Louisa County Industrial Park (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Louisa County Poor House (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Louisa County Public Library (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Louisa Hotel (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Louisa - Main Street (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Lyles (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Luce Mine (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Macedonia Church Cemetery (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Mahoney (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Mallory (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Maps (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Masonic Lodge #58, Louisa - Members (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Masonic Lodge (Mineral, VA) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Massey (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - May Residence (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - McGehee (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Methodist Church (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Miller's Market (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Mineral Auto Parts Building (Whitlock) (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Mineral Avenue (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Mineral Baptist Church (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Mineral Baptist Church Cemetery (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Mineral - Buildings (Box 41, Folder 15-18)
  - Mineral - Buildings (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
  - Mineral Centennial Celebration - 4 August 1990 (Box 42, Folder 4-8)
  - Mineral Elementary School Faculty (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Mineral Fire and Rescue Trucks (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Mineral - First Street (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Mineral High School (Box 42, Folder 12-13)
  - Mineral High School - Class Photos (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Mineral High School - Class Photos (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Mineral High School - Faculty (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Mineral High School - Sports Teams (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Mineral Jail (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Mineral - Louisa Avenue (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Mineral Milling Company (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Mineral - Miscellaneous People (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Mineral Post Office (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Mineral Tea Room (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Mineral - Third Street (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Mineral Water Works (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Mines - Miscellaneous and Unidentified (Box 43, Folder 12-13)
  - Mining Company Seals (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Minter (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Cemetery Markers (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Identified Photographs (Box 43, Folder 17-18)
  - Miscellaneous Unidentified Photographs (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Moore (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Morrison Gold Mine (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Mt. Hermon Baptist Church (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Neeley (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - William C. Nelson Mill on Contrary Creek (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Nelson-Ware-Butler Residence (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers, Publications, etc. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Noel (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Peyton Noel Residence (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - North Anna Power Plant (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Oak Grove Cemetery (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Oakland Cemetery (Louisa, VA) (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Ogg Memorial Building (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Old Tolersville Road (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Old Tolersville Road Drainage Project (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Oliver (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Ore Samples (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Parades (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
  - Payne (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Pendleton (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Dr. E. Barbour Pendleton Residence (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Pendleton's Depot (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Pennington, E.C. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Peoples (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Peregoy (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Pets (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Peyton Place (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Porter (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Proffitts Corner (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Purcell (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Putty, Leroy (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Quarles (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Quilt (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Radio Equipment/Operators (Box 45, Folder 18-19)
  - Restricted Photos (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Rhoades (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Richmond, VA (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Right-of-Way Project - 522 N (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Right-of-Way Project - 522 N (Box 46, Folder 1-5)
  - Road to Kiblinger Farm (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Rockingham County Cemetery Markers (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Rohr (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Rough & Ready Iron Furnace (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - "Roundabout" (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Rudinger Residence (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Runnet (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Sacra (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Sacra, James (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Safley (Box 46, Folder 15-16)
  - Frank Safley Residences (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - George E. Safley Residence (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - St. John's Chapel (Louisa County, VA) (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - St. John's Chapel (Mechanicsville) (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - St. John's Episcopal (Spotsylvania County) (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - St. Jude Catholic Church (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Savage (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Schooler Family Cemetery (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Schools - Louisa County (also Class Photos) (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - "Scotchtown" (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Scraptown (Armenius Mines) (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Henry Sharp Residence (Pendleton, VA) (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Mae Payne Shelton Gravesite (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Shumake (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Simms, Thomas (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Sims (Box 47, Folder 15-16)
  - Emmitt Sims Residence (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Jack Sims Residence (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Skwarlo (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Smith/Safley Descendants - Charlottesville, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Snow/Ice Storms/Weather (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Sonntag (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Spicer (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Spicer/Jarrell Visit - May 1994 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Spicer, Wallace & Eleanor - 50th Anniversary (10 February 1991) (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - C.C. Spicer Residence (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Sterling Poultry Farm (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Strickler (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Elton Strong and Walbrook Swank (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Sulphur Mines (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Talley/Shealor (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Genie Talley Residence (Pendleton, VA) (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Tate (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Terrell (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Thomas, Sarah C. - Funeral, 14 June 1991 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Thompson (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Adam Toler - Ciphering Book (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Tolersville/Toler Descendants (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Tolersville Tavern/Mineral Hotel (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Tour DuPont, 1993/Bikers (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Towsey Cemetery (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Trains (Box 49, Folder 4-6)
  - Travel (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Tredegar Iron Works (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Trevilian Depot (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Trice (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Richard Trice Building (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Trinity Baptist Church (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Tulloh (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Turner, Edward (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - V.W. Turner Residence and Store (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - TV Images (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Twin Vein Mine (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - U.S. Constitution Plaque Dedication, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Victoria Furnace (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Victoria Furnace Tram Road R/O Way (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Vision Quest Wagon Train (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Waldrop Church Cemetery (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Walton Gold Mine on Contrary Creek (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Walton and Wood Motor Company/Store (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Ware-Butler-Sims Cemetery (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Ware-Butler-Sims Residence (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Martha Washington Birthplace (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Watkins (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Wheeler (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Wheeler, James Kennedy (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Whitlock (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Whitlock's Store (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Bartholomew Whitlock Residence (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - John H. Whitlock Cemetery (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Wilson (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Wind-Swept Pines at Kiblingers (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Wood (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Woodlawn Cemetery (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - World War II - People and Places (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
  - Photograph Albums (Box 52)
  - Slides (Box 53)
- Oversize and Other Items (Box 54-61)
  This series includes much of the same types of material contained in the rest of the collection, but are housed elsewhere because of their size. There are files on Armenius Mines, census records, Contrary Plantation, court records, deeds, diplomas, railroad plans and specifications, maps and plats, marriage records, military service records, photographs, and publications. Also included in this series is ephemera, unused postcards, publications, and ledgers. There are numerous ledgers of the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway, including block registers, car reports, freight claims, monthly time books, way bills, and loose papers. There is also a ledger of Pleasants Cash Store in Bumpass, a time roll of the Grasselli Chemical Company, and day books belonging to John H. Kennedy.
  - Armenius Mines - Time Roll and Employee Accounts (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Census Records (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Contrary Plantation (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Court Records (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Deeds (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Diplomas (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Freight & Passenger Depots - Plans and Specifications (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Kiblinger-Butler Marriage Records (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Maps and Plats
  - Military Service Awards and Certificates (Frank L. McLean) (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Publications (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - The Soldier's Paper - 15 January 1865 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Ephemera (Box 55)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Block Register (Box 56)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Car Report Book (Box 56)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Freight Claims (Box 56)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Freight Conductors Record (Box 56)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Monthly Time Book (Box 56)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Time Book (Box 57)
  - Ledgers - C & O Railway - Way Bills and Loose Papers (Box 57)
  - Ledgers - Pleasant's Cash Store (Bumpass) - Invoice Book (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous Ledgers, Account Books, and Memorandum Books (Box 59)
  - Grasselli Chemical Company - Time Roll and Employee Accounts
  - John H. Kennedy - Day Books, 1894-1895 (3 vols.)
  - Postcards (Box 60)
  - Publications (Box 61)